<!-- Plugin Configuration File. Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-configuration-file.html -->
<idea-plugin>
    <!-- Unique identifier of the plugin. It should be FQN. It cannot be changed between the plugin versions. -->
    <id>com.codigrate.color-picker.plugin</id>

    <!-- SemVer -->
    <version>2026.1.0</version>

    <!-- Public plugin name should be written in Title Case.
         Guidelines: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/marketplace/plugin-overview-page.html#plugin-name -->
    <name>Color Picker</name>
    <category>UI</category>

    <!-- A displayed Vendor name or Organization ID displayed on the Plugins Page. -->
    <vendor email="info@codigrate.com" url="https://codigrate.com">Codigrate</vendor>

    <idea-version since-build="252"/>

    <!-- Description of the plugin displayed on the Plugin Page and IDE Plugin Manager.
         Simple HTML elements (text formatting, paragraphs, and lists) can be added inside the <![CDATA[ ]]> tag.
         Guidelines: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/marketplace/plugin-overview-page.html#plugin-description -->
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            A complete color companion for your JetBrains IDE. Pick any color on your screen with the
            eyedropper, then read everything about it in one tool window: conversions across every
            common color space, WCAG accessibility checks, harmony schemes, tint and shade ramps and
            color temperature.
            <br/>
            <br/>
            <b>Features</b>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Eyedrop anywhere.</b> Sample any pixel on your screen: your code, a design tool,
                    an image, anything you can see.</li>
                <li><b>Conversions.</b> Hex, RGB, RGB %, Web-Safe, Decimal, Octal, Binary, HSL, HSV,
                    HWB, OKLCH, OKLab, CIE-LAB, CIE-LCH, CMYK, nearest RAL Classic, XYZ, Yxy and
                    Hunter Lab, each one click to copy.</li>
                <li><b>Copy-ready CSS.</b> The color as text, background, border, text shadow and box
                    shadow rules.</li>
                <li><b>Accessibility.</b> WCAG 2 contrast ratio and APCA (WCAG 3) of the color as text
                    on white, black and its complementary, both directions, with AA and AAA verdicts
                    for normal and large text.</li>
                <li><b>Color channels.</b> The screen (RGB, HSL, HSV) and print (CMYK) channel mix as
                    bars.</li>
                <li><b>Harmony.</b> Complementary, analogous, monochrome, split complementary, triadic
                    and tetradic companions from the color wheel, one click away.</li>
                <li><b>Tints, shades and tones.</b> The color stepped toward white, black and gray;
                    click a step to load it.</li>
                <li><b>Temperature.</b> Whether the color reads warm or cool, with its warmer and cooler
                    neighbours.</li>
                <li><b>Color vision deficiency.</b> The color beside its simulation under protan, deutan,
                    tritan and monochromacy vision, from mild to severe.</li>
                <li><b>Recent colors.</b> Your last picks stay in the tool window, so the shades you are
                    working with are always one click away.</li>
            </ul>
            <br/>
            <b>Getting Started</b>
            <ol>
                <li>Install a compatible JetBrains IDE, such as IntelliJ IDEA, CLion, PyCharm, or other IntelliJ-based IDEs.</li>
                <li>Launch the IDE and open plugin settings.</li>
                <li>Search for <b>Color Picker</b> and click install.</li>
                <li>After installing the plugin, open the <b>Color Picker</b> tool window from the right sidebar, or run <b>Tools | Pick a Color</b>. Press <b>Pick a Color</b> and use the eyedropper to sample any pixel on your screen.</li>
                <li>Click any value row to copy it, click any chip to explore that color, and collapse the sections you do not use. The tool window remembers your layout.</li>
            </ol>
            <br/>
            Part of the Codigrate tools family, alongside the in-browser
            <a href="https://codigrate.com/tools/color">color</a>,
            <a href="https://codigrate.com/tools/palette">palette</a> and
            <a href="https://codigrate.com/tools/gradient">gradient</a> tools and the
            Codigrate themes for JetBrains IDEs.
        ]]>
    </description>

    <!-- Short summary of new features and bugfixes in the latest plugin version.
         Displayed on the Plugin Page and IDE Plugin Manager. Simple HTML elements can be included between <![CDATA[ ]]> tags. -->
    <change-notes>
        <![CDATA[
            <b>2026.1.0</b>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Initial release: screen eyedropper with a magnifier
                </li>
                <li>
                    Conversions across every common color space, with copy-ready CSS
                </li>
                <li>
                    WCAG 2 and APCA readability checks
                </li>
                <li>
                    Harmony schemes, tints, shades and tones, and color temperature
                </li>
                <li>
                    Color vision deficiency simulations and recent colors
                </li>
            </ul>
        ]]>
    </change-notes>

    <!-- Product and plugin compatibility requirements.
         Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-compatibility.html -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow id="Color Picker"
                    anchor="right"
                    icon="/icons/pickerToolWindow.svg"
                    factoryClass="com.codigrate.colorpicker.ColorPickerToolWindowFactory"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="Codigrate.ColorPicker.Pick"
                class="com.codigrate.colorpicker.PickColorAction"
                text="Pick a Color"
                description="Open the Codigrate color picker and sample a color from the screen"
                icon="/icons/pipette.svg">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
